<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BSSRDF on Shih-Chin</title>
    <link>http://shihchin.com/tags/bssrdf.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in BSSRDF on Shih-Chin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Shih-Chin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://shihchin.com/tags/bssrdf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Realistic Human Skin with Normalized Diffusion &amp; GGX</title>
      <link>http://shihchin.com/2015/12/realistic-human-skin-with-normalized-diffusion--ggx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shihchin.com/2015/12/realistic-human-skin-with-normalized-diffusion--ggx.html</guid>
      <description>After implementing BSSRDF importance sampling for Normalized Diffusion and GGX BRDF, I started wondering how realistic could the appearance of human skin be achieved with the combination of these two models. The whole development process is quite interesting, because it&amp;rsquo;s a perfect combination of my two interests: programming and photography. With only one diffusion layer and two specular layers on top, I tried to find the way to make it as realistic as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSSRDF Importance Sampling of Normalized Diffusion</title>
      <link>http://shihchin.com/2015/10/bssrdf-importance-sampling-of-normalized-diffusion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shihchin.com/2015/10/bssrdf-importance-sampling-of-normalized-diffusion.html</guid>
      <description>Highly scattering materials like milk or skin can&amp;rsquo;t be precisely modeled by BRDF only, because light would scatter multiple times before exiting the material at different locations. Bidirectional surface scattering distribution function (BSSRDF) is used to describe radiance transfer across the surface boundary with diffusion profile for multiple scattering events.
To solve subsurface light transport efficiently, there are several approaches to model and evaluate the diffusion profile. Recently, Burley [5] has proposed an artist-friendly diffusion profile with only two exponential functions and the most attracting thing is that it&amp;rsquo;s not only intuitive for artists to use but also faster to evaluate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>