<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Shih-Chin</title><link>https://shihchinw.github.io/page.html</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Shih-Chin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © Shih-Chin</copyright><atom:link href="https://shihchinw.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arnold</title><link>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/arnold.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/arnold.html</guid><description>General Resources Autodesk Arnold (YouTube) Arnold Support Corner alShaders - Wonderful 3rd party Physically-Based Shaders by Anders Langlands. Maya to Arnold User Guide Tutorial Video Tutorials Tips &amp;amp; Tricks Render Tips for MtoA Using &amp;ldquo;Min Pixel Width&amp;rdquo; with Care for Hair/Fur Rendering Removing Noise Case Studies How Arnold was used on Gravity - An exclusive interview with Martin Preston. Articles &amp;amp; Interviews Marcos and Arnold, by Eric Haines and Marcos Fajardo.</description></item><item><title>Computer Graphics</title><link>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/computer-graphics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/computer-graphics.html</guid><description>General Resources Introduction to Computer Graphics - A great introductory video series by Cem Yuksel. Physically Based Rendering in Filament - A comprehensive introduction to PBR. fxguide - Comprehensive and in-depth articles about VFX production. Real-Time Rendering Resources from &amp;ldquo;Real-Time Rendering&amp;rdquo; 4/e. Graphics Books - A detailed book list about computer graphics. Computer Graphics Research Software (Last updated in 2012) flipcode (Last updated in 2004) Research Ke-Sen Huang&amp;rsquo;s Home Page - Paper collections for SIGGRAPH/EG/I3D/EGSR Quasi Complete Online SIGGRAPH Course Notes (99-07) How to Create a Graphics Research Paper by Morgan McGuire SIGGRAPH Links of Courses &amp;amp; Talks by Stephen Hill 2022, 2021, 2020, 2019 Common mistakes in technical writing by Wojciech Jarosz Confessions of a researchaholic by Li-Yi Wei Tips for Giving Clear Talks by Kayvon Fatahalian Computer Animation Technology Publications from Disney Animation Pixar Online Library Physics-Based Animation, maintained by Christopher Batty Sony Pictures Imageworks (Last updated in 2011) Autodesk Research Real-time Techniques GDC Valut NVIDIA Research Publications Intel Graphics Research AMD GPU Open: Research Publications Frostbite engine Valve Square Enix Course Materials Polygon Mesh Processing Graphics Cources at CMU Parallel Computer Architecture and Programming by Kayvon Fatahalian.</description></item><item><title>Global Illumination</title><link>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/global-illumination.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/global-illumination.html</guid><description>General Resources Equation: Quantifying Light = Great 3-D Animation @WIRED The State of Rendering @fxguide. Part1, Part2. Comprehensive introduction for current state of rendering research. ompf2 Wonderful forum about ray tracing implementation and researching. GI in Production Great materials for artists, TDs and R&amp;amp;D engineers.
The Comprehensive PBR Guide Vol 1 &amp;amp; 2, from allegorithmic. Global Illumination Across Industries. SIG'10. Raytracers and workflow: a production perspective. SIG'14. The Quest for the Ray Tracing API.</description></item><item><title>Maya</title><link>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/maya.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shihchinw.github.io/page/maya.html</guid><description>General Resources Maya Developer Center Maya Documentation Maya Learning Channel @YouTube Maya Training Material (a little outdated, but still useful) Duncan&amp;rsquo;s Corner Maya Python programming for production by Chris Zurbrigg. Maya Programming Forums Autodesk AREA CG-Society Highend3D Programming Maya Scripting Primer. New To The Api? Then Read This! by Robert Bateman. Maya API: Where to start!?!??!? at Maya Station. Maya How-To&amp;rsquo;s by Bryan Ewert. A comprehensive collection of the tips for MEL &amp;amp; API!</description></item></channel></rss>